The Sixth Year is a comedy, drama film directed by Rick Alverson.
The Sixth Year is an art world drama series in five episodes,
which re-interprets the format of the TV series.
Set in the New York art world, it stages the backstage and theatricalizes the social interactions
and power games, the aspirations, passions, and everyday realities of the field.
The screenplay is based on interviews with artists, curators, gallerists, collectors, and art advisors,
whose opinions, anecdotes, and gossip it abstracts and extrapolates into a fictional narrative.
Matt (first segment), played by Kentucker Audley.
Alexis (third segment), played by Anna Bak-Kvapil.
Sy (first segment), played by Dustin Guy Defa.
Chris (fifth segment), played by Keith Poulson.
All of Episode 4, played by Bob Hennessey.
Episode 4 Narrator, played by Bob Hennessey.
The Sixth Sense is a 1999 American psychological
thriller film written and directed by M.
Night Shyamalan.
It stars Bruce Willis as a child psychologist whose patient (Haley
Joel Osment) claims he can see and talk to the dead.
Released by Buena Vista Pictures through its Hollywood Pictures label on August 6, 1999, The Sixth Sense was well received by critics and was nominated for six Academy Awards,
including Best Picture, Best Director and Best Original Screenplay for Shyamalan, Best Supporting Actor for Osment, and Best Supporting Actress for Collette.
The film established Shyamalan as a preeminent filmmaker of thrillers and introduced the
cinema public to his traits, most notably his affinity for twist endings.
The film was a commercial success, grossing over $672 million worldwide, becoming the
second-highest-grossing film of 1999 and Shyamalan's highest-grossing film to date.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.